all right well we got Nate ansmann again
what's up my friend welcome to the
junkyard love podcast again I'm happy to
be here yeah I'm having a regular thing
now it's definitely gonna be a regular
thing and we're gonna just both be
improvement together out loud and so in
order to do that we've got to be making
sure everybody's willing to accept
change
ain't that right so Nate and I've been
talking a lot about change and how
important it is for like our lives you
know me but you know you've been through
a lot of change and it's it's hard to
have other people around us not fully
accepting it or understanding how how
insane an in-depth change really is so
let's get going on change what's your
feelings on this it's crazy isn't I've
had so many positive positive positive I
would say responses to the stuff that
I'm trying to do the youtubes the
messages you know that I just break down
in everyday life the way that I'm trying
to help people but the craziest part is
that the people that I thought would be
supporting me are the people that almost
fail to see it
which is it's almost like they think
it's a persona that I'm putting off they
don't think that it's real change they
think it's like oh well you know that's
what's popular right now is growth and
change and all this kind of stuff and
it's like this is what I'm living you
know like I because I've seen results
and because I've seen change in not only
in myself but the deliveries that I do
I've seen change in other people already
and I've you know people are reaching
out to me that I don't even know we're
like yo you're changing my life like you
know you droppin truth problems yeah
making people watch i watch i watch one
of your videos at this girl messaged me
she's from California she rides I was in
a restaurant and I was watching one of
your videos and I just started crying
and I'm like and I talk about this thing
I have this quote I was like shout out
to the the strangers that show more love
than the neighbors and it's I was you
know the people that are you know like I
said the people that I really thought
we're gonna be supportive I think
they're they don't think that I'm
about it and it's hard for they aren't
allowing you to change from the view
that they have of you yes so not so I've
changed but their view on me hasn't
changed and so you know I think a lot of
people especially people that I've known
for the longest they're like what's he
doing like he ain't like that like he
and deep like that I know you Bree I
know you ain't deep like that but it's
like we used to but when we were in
sixth grade we don't have room in this
world to stay on a sixth grade selves
are not gonna happen to be happen yeah
so it's it's it's been a little bit of
wake up but at the same time I'm
embracing every part of it like maybe
you know I have this difficulty trying
to figure out whether I'm around to help
that person and help them grow and help
them help them you know level up and and
in doing that and everywhere I can
because that's what I want to do I want
to serve and I want to be able to to
help everybody around me so am I there
to help them or am i outgrowing them
right you know what I mean and that's
been hard for me because I'm like okay
so in Who I am and in who I want to be
everybody thinks I gotta figure it out
you know I mean a lot of people
especially from the outside people you
know like you know bro I can't wait to
be like that I can't wait to be like you
I can't wait to be you know have
everything you know like I don't have to
figure it out
I'm still trying to figure out well does
the Nate that I'm supposed to be is the
Nate that I'm trying to be does he look
at people and say you ain't you're not
matching my energy do I leave you behind
or do I pick you up and bring you with
me and I'm an awful I think it's
situational but I want to bring people
with me yeah you definitely do I mean I
feel like there's so many stories you
tell me are are of you taking the extra
time to stay behind and be like I'm not
willing to just to just we're on the
same energy so see you later
you you want like that you do really try
to keep to bring people with you first
I tell I'm still again I don't have it
all figured out so I'm still working I
would do not would absolutely love to
quit my job and just
sooo this and just you know go all in
but I you know matter its matter I'm
patients the ego wants it right my boss
she's very like quick to cut people off
and no grace and and I have a great
relationship with her and you know I
told her like you know she like you know
we need to get rid of so-and-so and I
told her I was like I will not fire
anybody I will help them and I will I
will give him the ultimatum and I will
say you will change with me or you will
quit but I will not fire you and I told
her the reason that I'm like that is
because if someone didn't give me that
grace not in my professional life but in
my personal life I wouldn't be here
right now
I wouldn't be here I wouldn't be sitting
here with you I wouldn't I don't know
where I would be so if someone didn't
give me that no I'm not gonna let you
stay down on the ground I'm gonna pick
you up and every time you fall I'm gonna
pick you up even when you can't pick
yourself up I'm gonna pick you up if
someone didn't do that for me I wouldn't
be here so I I won't leave people behind
but also to like I said I don't have it
all figured out do I work on myself work
on myself working myself and build up
this this energy and this this capacity
to where I'd never run out of gas and
that way I can pick up as many people as
I want or do I pick up people along the
way and do I am i sacrificing myself a
little bit just a little bit you know I
mean I don't think I'm sacrificing
myself but I mean in a way I'm spending
time on my own progression to help
somebody your cup so much that it's that
it's falling falling over yeah yeah
you've got a little bit to give so
you're giving it exactly so you know I I
battled that sometimes I'm like you know
am i none of my wasting my time because
I don't know everything help is a waste
of time because like I said if someone
didn't help me I wouldn't be here but
there's times where I'm like you know if
I get to it if I level up again I have
more to give do I am I in a spot to be
helping this person basically is what I
kind of think about sometimes like
mentally like do I need to learn more do
I need to have more experience in order
to help this person and so you
I battle that I battle that sometimes
but at the same time I'm like if I just
believe in myself like yo you can help
this person like I want to poor I want
to poor I want to poor and that's my
goal and someone asked me that like
what's your goal with all this like what
is and it's to never run out of gas
never like I can I'm so confident myself
I'm so confident I'm so confident my
ability I'm so confident in what I do
and what I stand for that no matter what
you do to me no matter what you say to
me no matter what your actions are I'm
never gonna take it personal and I'm
gonna and I'm gonna bring you with me
and in my I have this vision of like
what nasty a is and what what the
business is and what what the movement
is and I just like have this picture of
like me and it's like a picture of my
face and this and then this camera just
like walks out you know walks backwards
and it's just like a bunch of people
behind me and I brought all these people
with me like in every sense of the word
like they were they were lost and you
know and they and they heard my voice
and they came to it you know I mean at
Earth right bro okay so one of my
favorite artists is John belly and he
has this video for a he designed the art
for it and I think he drew it up for
luxury is the name of the video
essentially it's through the whole video
to him over his years and he's got this
he's like afraid of his monsters he's
afraid of the dark he's got this candle
and he's like oh there's demons
everywhere he's running from but over
through his career he shows that he
tells the story of by the end of it he's
alone in this black room he's got his
candle and he's like you know like early
ages 20s like he's where he is now and
then he starts to notice little lights
flicker around at the end of the music
video and he sees all the people with
their candles that he gave permission
you know it's a you know it's a deepened
interpretation of the movie but that's
how it is you know when when you stay
strong in the dark with your flame you
know eventually the people who are on
the dark and magma and I've been
watching that flame for a while like is
he doing something like is he you know
should we do that and then they light
theirs and they they get permission so
you're doing that I mean it's it's hard
it's worth every second but but feeling
that you're going to lose friends or
lose family or be misunderstood
because people are allowing you to
change it's just it just seems a world
where we don't allow change seems what
can we possibly get done yeah I think
that's one of the like I said it's one
of the things that I still battle is
like you know I I love Who I am right
now I really do but it's like if you
can't see me for who I am like is that
is that going against my end goal is to
leave you behind you know I mean so as
much as as much as I know what I want
that's something that I ponder all the
time is that I'm confident in this this
is what I want this is who I am this is
who I'm supposed to be and I will not
give it up I can't because I I refuse to
go back like I was in the design you
animals I was in the deepest deepest
depths of depression and what it is to
just be miserable like every day I woke
up in misery every day I woke up and
hated what I was doing hated who I was
hated what I represented I will not go
back there but was I connecting with
those people because they were that as
well and can they connect with the
higher me you know I mean so I think
about that as much as you know I I now
I'm in this place where I don't
overthink
I still think you know I still have my
times or I'm laying in bed and I can't
sleep because I'm like yo like you know
these people have you know been your
friends for so long and family members
you know I mean it's like stuff do you
leave them behind and and in what I
really really think about it the answer
is no because that's not what I stand
for and that's not what like my my
mission is but at the same time it's
like I can only you can't see the light
if you don't want to see it well you got
to control your own energy to exactly
that I mean you giving all your energy
to trying leaves you with nothing yeah
yeah so I made up this thing I call it
like the energy bank right so
everybody's finances are different
everybody's got a different amount of
money
you know and and so I made it up like a
card like certain people can only spend
so much like you can wake up like people
that differ between you and I can wake
up and then go get gassed and go get
lunch thing go get dinner and there just
boom boom boom swipe swipe so on Amazon
you know I'm saying all day people like
us that are trying to do something and
we're budgeting and we're you know we're
working less to work on our passion like
we don't have so much to spend you know
and I feel it's the same way with your
energy like when you build your energy
up I can all day bro all day like it's
nothing but if you're in a spot where
you haven't built that up and you're so
negative and I feel like you have
positive energy and you got negative
energies but you know in your persona
like when we talked about the good wolf
the bad wolf the good energy the
battering the monster the waking up on
the other side of the bed everyone you
get it whichever one you're feeding how
much can I spend some people are
spending negative energy all day right
and then asking why and then you're just
giving it out giving it out giving it
out but you only have so much good
positive energy to give out one day they
might give it out right when they wake
up like they might give it to their
spouse and then BOOM they're miserable
at work to their phone give it to their
phone they're miserable at work they're
miserable after work those are the
people to have road rage like when you
cut somebody off and you're like oh you
know I'm sorry I'm sorry I'm sorry in
there freaking out flipping you off and
cussing at you that I use that the road
rage thing so I think that my my goal is
to just build up this Bank where I'm all
positive of course you can't control
everything so I'm gonna have those
thoughts sometimes but be ready to
handle them I'm just like let me let me
swipe it on you like let me give it out
give it out give it out like I got so
much the way that like the way people
spend I can just give this energy out
all those swiping it so I predict
exactly and that's that's my goal in its
but in that change can I do that with
certain people that don't want it you
know I mean because then am i dumping
into cups with holes in them and there's
that exhaust me I don't know yet
but I'm willing to try it and willing to
find out yeah I mean III did the same
thing I had friends that I
I just had to I had to be clear and like
I can't do this thing that we're doing
anymore and for the for these things it
was negativity I was like I you know I'm
finding my own brain here I hope that
you would understand I don't want to be
around this negativity and you know it's
obviously a more in-depth conversation
that but that's the essence of what I
said and it didn't go well and I haven't
talked to that friend since it's been
over a year and that was one of my very
good friends and I think that that's
important but I will say that I did try
you know I tried to tell them understand
change but it's a hard conversation we
don't really have conversations about
change you don't have conversation yeah
it's uncanny
please understand why those comfortable
oh man yeah it's so uncomfortable I had
to have an experience like that too I
have a buddy was drinking a lot drinking
a lot very violent when he was drinking
all the time you know I would tell him
because I was in a spot where we knew
each other we did that I move forward I
stopped drinking I don't drink at all I
don't I don't use any kind of drugs I
don't smoke weed I don't nothing and you
know he's still in it which is fine I
love you you know for who you are that's
that's completely okay but when I see it
destroying your life then I have a
problem because I care about you because
I'm your friend because I want better
for you a lot of people look at you know
Charlamagne tha God is of course yeah I
heard him say this one thing that
silence is a cosign and it blew my mind
right and so I'm like if I don't think
if I don't say anything
I'm co-signing to him ruining his life
and that was hurting me so I told him I
said bro I really think you need to
consider stop drinking you have a lot of
things going in your life you got school
you have a good job you're trying to be
a manager you got a baby on the way and
you know he was like you're right you're
right you're right
and I think in loving somebody you have
to hold them accountable too I saw him
like the this club and my girl worked
out the next weekend and I was like I'm
I'm done haven't talked to him since
goodbye your energy there you know but
it not you know it's not that he was
affecting me is that he was affecting
himself and I and I love him enough to
not allow him to do that like I can see
that totally you know I mean and so but
in that like we talked about before a
lot of people think it at that time that
that relationship was over and that it's
done because as Millennials when we're
sensitive when we're sensitive and when
we take things personal it's done forget
about it whatever forget about a whole
new era stopped no never again
I never have any I'll punch you in the
face if I see you exactly crazy I never
think that the relationships are
anything for that matter dreams or
relationships jobs everything I never
think anything is broken like I like
that thank you for that yeah like I feel
like I have something some thinking to
do about that I never think that
anything's broken I think things can
always be fixed in love and friendships
and relationships and so when he's ready
and in you know what's crazy sometimes
they even think what if I wasn't ready
like even though he was being
destructive what if I'm not the best
Nate and what if that Nate didn't give
him that message I needed what if I
didn't hit the correct nerve and the
second that I'm just I keep getting
better and I keep my speaking keeps
getting better in my thinking keeps
getting better and I keep getting more
analytical and more deep I can hit him
exactly where he needs to be hit right
so maybe I wasn't ready maybe it wasn't
him yeah or maybe just the far different
just the difference and where you guys
were and you know I've led you to
miscommunicate hardcore exactly I love
you so I need to do these things at all
he hears is and you're not almost
exactly and what is I think so special
about that is that how many people can
do that how many people can look at
somebody else and clearly see as a as
what's normal that that person's messing
up but I can look at myself and go you
know what maybe you had something to do
with that maybe you didn't say the right
message even though you're sober even
though you work even though you don't
drink even though you save your money
even though you do all this [__] that's
normal
maybe you were the problem
I am okay with taking that
responsibility in saying that maybe I
didn't communicate the best maybe I
could have loved him more maybe if I
knew him better maybe I could have got
through him you gotta be careful taking
responsibility that's not yours though
you know sometimes we put like
definitely with your passionate
motivational like side of going all-in
on everything like you got to make sure
that you ain't going all-in on yourself
I agree yeah I think there's a balance
it ain't easy I don't think there's an
answer and yeah I think that it's
something that we're on the process of
learning yeah again and I you know I
battle that sometimes I my gosh should I
give up too early you know I mean but
but I I want that like I said I want
that just just full tank just no no
running out of gas like I want that like
I want to be like if you walked up to me
and wanted to talk to me to air if I saw
him I wouldn't reach out to him over the
phone but if I saw him I would talk to
him I would tell him I loved him I would
say let's work this out no no questions
asked no no grudges held no nothing well
something that you learned just even
outside of if you had an argument or not
when you see like someone who you
haven't seen for a long time like this
something you notice how as we as we
approach the age of 30 and stuff I mean
there is that connection like oh we are
friends there's this connection still
there that like it sucks to have to
fight that with like oh we're friends I
care about this person but we got this
thing so they you know good for you for
being willing to to approach that do you
want to I want to talk about change at
like holidays I think that's a good
place for listeners to think about so
Christmas coming up you know we walk
through that door and a lot of times our
family is like here's this 15 year old
Ashley you know I'm saying and Ashley's
like I'm a grown woman I'm 30 yeah if
you're not letting me be 30 like let me
be an adult let me have a conversation
with you I'm allowed to have an opinion
you know I I think a lot of a lot of the
you know little advice that I give with
people about their relationship with
their parents now it's a lot of that
it's a lot of their parents don't seem
to be letting them be the be the woman
or be the man that they are now yeah I I
think that was the same thing that I was
talking about with you know the friends
are people that around me that don't see
the new me and don't see what I'm trying
to live it's it's similar it's like
because you don't see these people all
the time like you might have family
members that you see you know just on
Christmas like once a year
so they're stuck in where you've always
been and and not exactly where you're at
and in like I said it I posted a video
about love the other day on YouTube
stepping outside yourself if I only
think if I have this opinion to Jake
that when I met you like I didn't know a
lot about you all I knew is that I was
like you know we both got nice hair like
we're both tatted like we both we both
jacked like that's all I know about you
so if I look at you now I'm like all
right Jake still tatted like Jake still
in good shape Jake has nice hair that's
all I think about you but I like how I
gotta step outside me to love you
you know I'm saying and people don't do
that your family members don't do that
because they're so concerned about what
they think and what they thinks right
everyone thinks that their opinions
right nobody's open-minded so if I think
that Ashley it's the same Ashley that
she was last year what am I gonna think
yeah there's no there's no room for that
and there's no room for allowing new
things so I really think it comes down
to stepping outside yourself seeing
where that person's at and accepting it
you know and like I said a lot of people
haven't accepted the fact that this is
me and this is the me that's here to
stay I'm not going back
like I'm not you're not getting me like
I always tell people that like when
people try to I don't say it out loud
but when I hear a negative thought or I
hear something that was from before I
hear you know people wanting me to you
know you know I go talk to that girl or
go you know let's just do shots like you
know let's just do this I in my head I'm
like you not getting me like you know
you will not get me I will not break
this beast is too tough and and it's
crazy because people think it's so easy
just to say no but like all those
thoughts come back all those feelings
come back all of that that rush of like
cork you could easily just exactly and
just let it all out and I'm just I take
it so serious and I'm just like you not
getting me like I'm not going back there
because it was hell and I refuse to live
in it and so when you keep going back
and just just grabbing one more and
ripping other people
out of there yeah it's it's just it's a
scary thought but I feel like I've
always I've always been able to have
that control on what I want and so I
just tuned it somewhere else I've always
like okay like you know I I know I can
get up early I know I can eat right I
know I can do this so let me tune that
into everything in my life and it was
shutting out things that I didn't want I
just allowed so many things in my life
that I didn't want and I just let kept
letting it happen like oh you know like
it'll get better it's okay bad things
don't get better you get better and you
change the bad things stay the bad
things and they stay where you're at and
you got to shut him out and so I had to
learn how to do that I had to learn how
to be disciplined with positive thinking
and I had to learn how to be disciplined
and not letting negative creep into me
and creep into my creep into my zone and
creeping in my area like I'm like you
not getting me stay away stay away you
train yourself every day with that
training yeah every day I wake up and
I'm like I'm positive I read my my firm
ation I read my word I read my
everything is is positive and if it's
like if it's negative I don't have time
for it I really don't and it's hard
again with the change it's hard to think
that some people might not ever get
there
that you love that you want to be there
with you that one like it's like getting
trying to get somebody to jump over like
like jump over like a little stream and
like in they're scared of water you know
it's like go the other side is where we
want to be like yo let's dope over here
like if you can just know it looks scary
but it's a stream yeah yeah if you can
just see over the cuz it's not hard it's
not hard to get there it's really not
it's a it's making a decision you just
have to decide this is how I'm gonna
live my life this is how I'm gonna do it
this is how I'm gonna stay positive this
is how I'm gonna get to where I'm going
and you commit to it and you do it every
single day and I'm like yo I can see
over this hill you should see all the
stuff that I forget everything
everything that you want is over this
hill you just got to get over the stream
to do it it's okay just come on come on
I think that people think that they
can't change man we've got this like
thing where I know it's in my DNA to my
genetics it's my like man man what you
tell yourself is what you are what you
commit to what you identify as that is
what you are that's who you are if you
tell yourself I've had this conversation
with people about DNA in alcoholism and
drugs and all that kind of stuff
with where I was mentally I think
everything is possible change is so
possible no matter where you're at I I'm
gonna cross it a line here that's gonna
maybe I don't believe in it you're not
an alcoholic because your parents were
you're not a drug addict because your
parents were as much as it can be in
your blood I don't buy it dude like I
know it's science but I think that the
facts I think that your mind beats facts
any day I think that that energy beats
facts any day and I just I whatever you
tell yourself you are is what you are if
you tell yourself that story of my
parents are alcoholics this is what I
know this is what I that's what I did my
dad didn't show me how to be a good
partner I don't know how to be a man in
relationship well if I just commit to it
cuz that's what I did I would tell all
my all my girls why'd you cheat on me
why do you do this why do you do that
what do you I don't know how to do it
sorry
I don't know I have you accepted that's
how I am my dad made me this man
whatever made me nobody showed me how to
be a good partner nobody showed me how
to love a woman nobody my mom could tell
me as much as I can but when you see an
example I did what I saw I was I was
mentally abusive I was emotionally
abusive I cheated I I didn't treat
anybody with respect because that's what
I saw that's what I saw as normal so I
committed to that this is how I am
that's exactly what I said I said I'm my
dad son Apple don't fall far from the
tree just give us like a weird pride it
would have taken that you're like
whatever [__] it did yeah whatever this
is what I am and I I think that it's
[__]
we're being misdirected and we think
that's where we're stuck what do you
want to do when you want to learn
something you learn about it so that's
what I'm doing I read books like people
think it's funny because I don't dabble
in things that I that I don't want and
people think it's weird because I'm
single like when we like talk about
girls on Instagram and stuff I'm like I
don't look at that and they're like why
not you're single I'm like because I
know my girl wouldn't want that well
who's your girl I don't know but I know
that I know that she wouldn't she
wouldn't like that you know I mean I
don't right now like we talked about
before I'm Sullivan like I know that my
girl wouldn't want me sleeping around I
don't know who my girl is I really don't
I don't know who she is but I know she
wouldn't want me sleeping around you
know your starting line is is farther
different than other people so you got
to work a little harder and so instead
of being in the victim role and saying I
can't change this is just how I am I
need to grow who's gonna match these
whatever you're like no I got to start
back here but I'm willing to change I'm
gonna I'm gonna get that head start back
here that's just fine I know and I think
it's learning how to play your cards
like yo when you're some people when
you're born you might be get born ace
king queen whatever right that's not
what I was dealt in the relationship
Department I did not get dealt a good
hand in the relationship Department what
am I gonna do go fish that's what you're
gonna do I'm gonna analyze my my deck
yeah and I'm gonna see how to play it
but okay all right or chef or yeah a
whole new deck you know I mean what I
have to like you said the starting point
like I started way behind but what am I
gonna do say forget it give up oh well I
guess I can do it yeah can tie my shoes
and go home I ain't qualified to race
thank you that but now I mean I read
books on relationships I read how to be
a good partner and people think it's
crazy cuz I'm not what do you need to
know that because when I'm ready I'm
gonna be ready millennial is I will not
do something until I see a reward you
will not even get me to start until I
see your reward you have to do it
beforehand what if somebody asked me to
speak and I've never spoke before am I
speaker if I can't do it you have to
have faith man I gotta have the ammo
ready like I gotta I have a bra I got
ammo right now somebody walked in this
room was like lets you to speak a
message to my team done let's do it okay
same thing with my relationship if I
don't if I'm not ready
how can I do it I'm gonna walk in to a
relationship as a man and I'm gonna be
like y'all need to teach me nothing I'm
ready to go let's do it like you're
coming with me I'm leading this let's go
and you're the one who's responsible for
this because I've learned it because
I've learned it I've studied it and I've
arranged and I'm training myself I'm no
longer cheating I no longer have a
wandering mind I no longer think about
other women because I have control of
that part of me that's what it takes you
have to work on the weak stuff and make
it better
and that's how you complete you know
what you're doing yeah yeah bro well I I
I think that that's something we could
always come back and explore change
change is a huge thing you know this
podcast is about change really it's
about believing that you can change so I
mean I think that we're gonna come
circle back around this I think that
anything that we can do to convince
people that you don't have to suffer
where you're at you aren't the victim
you can change and when someone else is
like telling you that you can change
they're doing it out of love I think
that's an important thing so accepting
change allowing change making room for
change it's so important and all of it
it's all in your head by Russ would you
recommend that book oh yeah yeah it
rests he's dope I was I was following
him at the beginning of Soundcloud days
I feel like I would feel the obligation
to say that like you know have an
audience yes underground oh yeah no I
always have liked him though all right
man well so what I wanted to talk about
a little bit is we do got New Year's
coming up I talked with my friend
Spencer on the podcast about like our
our resolution so we're gonna sit down
together and kind of ride him out we're
actually have a little podcast where
we're gonna like me and him we're gonna
work on ours together - out loud maybe
somebody else could fall along with the
Penza that's coming up but in the
meantime you're a very motivational
person and we're gonna get a lot of
benefits from from talking about what
what your aspects and what your thoughts
are around New Year's resolutions here
so let's dive into that man New Year's
resolutions setting goals okay news
resolution
I think news resolution is about action
action I see a lot of thing down a
little bit on you yeah I see a lot of
people especially January January is
like the hardest month for me to be in
the gym because there's dude there's so
many people in the gym I feel like every
year I want to take January off because
I'm like this and then I can go in
February and like the gym will be clear
again it's so funny I never want to like
even when I'm joking about that I'm
always like please don't make yourself
feel that you're a burden by going to
the gym even when I joke about that I'm
always like man I hope that little joke
or whatever that little complaint that I
let myself have is not stopping people
from Mike I don't want to be another one
who ruins gym
I mean I I think I want to say health
and in every aspect mental and physical
I think should be everybody's top top
priority because I think that's before
everything if you're not mentally and
physically healthy you can do anything
you can't grind you can't work you can't
make you can't increase your income you
can't so that's what's most important I
think that's what should be on everybody
top of everybody's list is physical and
mental health I think in every sense of
the word progression if you don't feel
good about yourself you don't want to do
anything but how do you do that you have
to make yourself feel good about
yourself you have to do things that set
you up to make you feel good that's like
a lot of times when people ask me like
you know how do you have so much energy
for this how do you have so much energy
for that I do things that make me feel
good
some of those things I wish didn't make
me feel good like it I really don't feel
good waking up after 6:00 I really don't
like I feel great like it's a mental win
for me to get up as early as I can but I
know it's not good for my mental so I
have to fight that like not you you mean
like so you're saying like if you
I had a late night last night but I
still want to get up at 5:00 a.m. yeah
it makes me it makes me feel like I'm
grinding right so what about balance
yeah that hustling yeah I didn't think
got a little too muddy I think yeah I so
I I make sure that my mental is taken
care of before my physical and in doing
that I gotta get rest but I I really I
really want this year I think everyone
needs to take their mental and physical
health physical health especially very
serious if you look at yourself and
you're consistently doing things to help
you be more healthy in a physical way
your confidence level goes up your
confidence level goes up like I feel
good like I'm I'm being consistent I'm
caring about myself that's self-love is
to take care of what you have taking
care of your body taking care of your
mind taking care of even though you know
I I don't want to make this about
physical and make it about flesh because
I firmly don't believe in that what you
are given this is your motor your body's
your motor if you don't take care of it
it's not gonna drive yeah just start
there we think that we need to go and
like just you show up at the gym feeling
like crap and just run through a workout
and just you know force through it I
feel like there's so many steps before
that that people do miss it there really
is yeah I actually wrote down for New
Year's and your New Year's fitness goals
I wrote down some things that I want to
touch on okay yeah let's explore these
number one I talked about in our last
meeting check your ego people get so
worried about what they're gonna look
like in the gym well I'm out of shape so
when I go in the gym there's all these
people that are in shape I'm gonna look
stupid I don't want to wear a certain
thing because I don't over I'm
overweight I'm fat I'm this I'm that I
don't know how to use the weights I
don't know how to use the machines I
don't know how to use any of it if your
ego was involved and you care what
people think and you're embarrassed
you're not gonna continue to go because
everybody hasn't learning ever it's it's
learning for everybody I I didn't know
what I was doing when I first started
lifting in sixth grade of course the PE
teacher would direct us a little bit but
I would literally walk up to the Machine
there's
those little drawings on there I would
read it I was like okay this works my
chest mmm down I lay down I go up and I
go down even if you don't do it right
you're gonna figure out how to do it
right when I was in the 6th grade I
remember doing the flat bench thing I
only used my arms so I wasn't using my
chest but this there was one time where
I felt it in my chest and I was like oh
that's what it's supposed to feel like
like and then I changed the way I laid
on the bench and I changed my posture
and I changed all these things but
because I didn't care I'm like yo I'm
just here to I'm here to get better like
it's not about what you think about me
I'm here to get better you have to check
that part of yourself because you've
been willing to fail you have to be
willing to fail because if you don't
like you're never even gonna start you
know I I do this with with basketball
basketball something I never played
organized sports growing up but
basketball I have a hoop in the driveway
and now that I if I'm not touring I'm
working from home and so I'm I've got to
do things to keep saying and go outside
so I shoot basketball and I have been
getting better and better but something
that I noticed that I had to fight at
the beginning which was something I
didn't even know existed in my brain was
like a car would drive by I'd be I'd be
in my bag I'm in my zone and car drive
by and I would notice like I would kind
of posture as if I like okay I gotta I
gotta make sure I'm making this shot
just in case they see it or I've got a I
gotta make sure I'm making shots you
know and then my neighbors started
coming over and playing some one-on-one
and I started trying to the oh he's on
his porch let me show out so I feel like
we do these things even when we think
we're good at other things you forgot
what it was you forgot what a waste to
you yeah like I think you for that
people forget what it is they forget
that the fact that they're going into to
get in good shape and to be healthier
and they start thinking about something
else like you were thinking about it's a
competition that's not why you walked
out there in the first place and picked
up the ball okay there cuz I love myself
and I want to be healthy and I want to
enjoy this life and I got a dope-ass
like my life is super concentrate and
then the second one don't overcomplicate
it alright okay so just go like you
don't need brand new shoes you don't
need you don't need workout gear you do
not need sup
I took you I take zero supplements I
take a green which is natural I take an
omega-3 because I don't need a lot of
fish I take a multivitamin that's it
I do recommend honestly all three of
those to anybody who's but but again
that [__] Slater like I feel like yeah
and but honestly yeah you know I think I
mean those are the bare bones I just
started taking those like I took a break
from supplements for a very long time
because I was like can I get everything
from food and I believe you can but I
think there's some holes that I was a
little bit of holes I was missing like I
said it sends you down holes that like
you don't really need to deal with if
you're just trying to get healthy and
live it unless you're trying to be a
bodybuilder all this no you don't really
need to deal with too much of that at
the beginning exactly yeah so just go
like don't over complicate it don't
don't make it this big thing you don't
gotta go to the best biggest gym you
don't have to go you know why don't I
don't have time and this gyms on open
this late like you you make it's so hard
that you don't want to do it when it's
just like all I have to do is whenever I
have times go to the gym that's it
once I'm one step at a time cool and
then when things start to progress it's
like looking at the top of the mountain
instead of taking the first step that's
what people do you're like I have to get
up there forget about it which means
what like oh I got it yeah I got to put
it on my shoes like what she's never
gonna wear it do I even have the right
shoes yeah man
I got to wake up I got to leave my oh I
didn't pack enough food you know we put
these long lists onto our stuff we're
talking man what is one all it is is
just go like just go whenever you have
time just go yeah and then after that
when it not whenever you do have time
but consistency and accountability so
make time you know so if you allotted
yourself time to go to the gym go to the
gym like hold yourself accountable with
whatever goals that you want I always
say life success everything fitness its
everything's custom if you have time the
time that you made to go to the gym if
you
committed to a certain diet hold
yourself accountable and be consistent
because fitness goals come with
consistency just like everything else if
you go to the gym once a week I'm sorry
you're not going to see results you know
you might be how much you dislike being
soared exactly this is silly and it's
not gonna give you what you want right
the same thing with you that's all I
will say though hang up on that real
quick if that's all you got if you're
low and that's all you know I've been
there I'm like I gotta go to the house
start start start start but definitely
man I I'm all for like you know setting
it long-term
yep make this but make this decision be
consistent stay accountable with
yourself and your diet and again with
the over complication don't over
complicate the diet either like we know
that eggs are healthy we know you know
some what we know lean meat is healthy
we know Shockley's better french fries
yeah we know we know vegetables are
healthy we know fruit is healthy start
with those things don't worry about how
much protein you're taking in don't
worry about how many square meals you're
eating a day people really obsess over
tell them yeah I don't count calories
just don't yourself don't do it don't
eat junk do not eat junk that's it's
very simple if you want to take it a
step further after that you start seeing
results you start learning things you
start learning things about your body
then you can you know maybe if you want
to take it that far take it that far I
don't I I just I find out what works for
me I do like to take in a lot of protein
because I feel like in the in the Jean
Department I'm a little low on the on
the muscle side so I taken a lot of
protein but I don't really keep track I
mean I know yeah you know what I mean I
just something just you well you've been
so into fitness and it's been such like
a it's a passion of yours it's something
that you it's your hobby it's to you
know it's a huge part of your life not
just a lot of people a lot of people
forget that it's like hey you're just
trying to be healthy and go to the gym
and kind of make sure you know a little
bit about the gym if they don't have to
know all these in-depth sometimes just
like we were talking about with the
podcast I was like oh man I gotta know
everything about video before I can
start a part no yeah oh I can't do it
yeah it knows to do the same thing no
maybe you just start strong audios I
don't know
started YouTube I don't know how to I
don't know how to shoot a vlog I may
cover the nails remember we were first
texting you like me and this the fun now
thumbnail but like that didn't stop you
or learn how to make the art or whatever
I had no idea yeah but you got to start
going you learn dude and then you can
take a couple you can look back make oh
I have learned those things you don't
have to have all the tools on your start
and your toolbox oh just get a new pin
and you can add them yeah and in there
okay so what about people can we talk
over what about people let's shout out
are like super introvert people who who
are like I'm not going to the gym it's
not gonna happen like what what do I you
know what about getting healthy if
you're not going to actually go to the
gym physical gym I can do a full body
workout at home inside I for for my
goals they're different I use and I use
weights to to to tailor towards my goals
but because it's about performance but
as far as being healthy you don't need
that like push-ups to work your chest
like push-ups to work your shoulders
planks to work your shoulders like
squats and squat jumps and and split
split squats and lunges to work your
legs like you don't you don't need any
of that if you if you really can't go to
the gym if you really don't want to put
yourself out there go on a jog like walk
if you walk fast you can burn some
calories I mean even outside of burning
calories I think just get in your
mindset like going for that walk before
like why don't you when you go for a
walk say alright I'm gonna workout at
home I'm gonna try this stupid thing I'm
not gonna go the gym I'm gonna try to
just do some push-ups and some stretches
on the ground for 20 minutes but I got
to get in the right headspace I'm gonna
go on a walk and I'm gonna just think
about like the positive things in my
life like what do I like you know try to
try to look for some beauty try to try
to not go on a walk and just like I'll
think about my bills and I gotta get
this workout done and let me do five
minutes of walking and time it like I
think give him the headspace of that
walk and you make it you make if you
make it a job you won't do it like oh
god I gotta go to the gym like and you
always got a trick your brain in a way
right you got a trick that beast or
something I tell people this with my
food like people are like don't you tire
your food like don't you're tired eating
the same thing every day and I say no
because I found the benefit in it
when you find the benefit in something
how do you get tired of it I go to the
gym it's crazy because everyone thinks
that just because I go that I want to
three out of the five days that I go I
probably don't want to go but the
benefit is is the performance the
benefit is healthy the benefit is
feeling good the benefit is the
self-confidence that I can look and go
when you put to me looking good it's not
about looking good it's the effort that
it took me to do that and I'm seeing
results that's what makes me feel good
is the fact that dude you put effort you
went when you didn't want to go you ate
what you not necessarily didn't want to
eat you you prepped your food you you
you went to the gym even when you're
retired putting in all that effort and
seeing something come out of it that's
what makes me feel good right and that
but people fail to see that because when
you first start working out or you
haven't worked out in a long time is the
hardest thing to do the hardest thing I
know so many people and it's crazy
because you know you we use this like
well I don't have a trainer I don't know
what you know what I want to do I see
people that I played high school sports
with are like overweight and they're
like getting a trainer it's like dude
you don't need a trainer you know what
you're doing like I remember you know
what you're doing well and even outside
of that man we you know saying you don't
know what you're doing is in a world of
YouTube you know I think a lot of people
feel that they need the word motivation
is is a little silly I think you know
and you could probably talk on this
pretty well because you're you know kind
of in the world you're a motivational
speaker you know that that narrows it
down too much but a lot of people are
like I I know what to do I just need
someone to motivate me right yeah and I
think I need motivation yeah well why
does it need the motivation to go to the
gym I need the motivation I just I just
don't have the motivation exactly it's
not it's not about it's the benefit I
really do it's like I don't always have
the motivation I don't but it's coming
up with something a routine like you're
let's get this bread thing right oh yeah
yeah okay so that's your pumpa for the
day what's your pump up for the gym
like people think that it's easy it's
not it's not dude I I do it like I said
oftentimes I don't want to go but the
second that I do my little thing and I
find the benefit like okay you need this
like you need this benefit the benefit
that I've created in my head I don't why
go to the gym I need that benefit and so
I do my little thing I turn on I turn on
some music I sit and if I don't want to
go to the gym I sit in the car I turn on
the music and I blast it and I sit right
in front of the gym I've turned the heat
all the way all the way on so I like
it's sweaty right just like I like I'm
already in there almost and then I'll
sit in there for a couple minutes and I
start yelling and I just go ahead no
just going that's what works for me
people might look at you think I'm crazy
but I've checked my ego I don't care
what what if you hear the lyrics of what
I'm singing I don't care if you hear I
ain't saying I don't write performance
for you yeah I don't care if you see me
sweating in the car and people like yeah
I'm getting in the zone yeah that's what
works for me ya know I want to encourage
people to do that more I think a lot of
us when were like I don't want to go to
the gym you know memes in social media
and just our pop culture has made it
kind of okay to insult yourself right
that like oh my fat ass before I go to
the gym everyday you know that because
I've been there and I laughed about it
plenty times in life is worth living
trust me no but like be weary you know
fear fear will sail in on the ship of
humor often oh yeah it'll it'll come for
you so when you're in your car and you
think about posting something you know
like trying to get my fat ass in the gym
or those sort of things just just chill
man instead instead of scrolling through
social media say churros yeah turn on
your favorite song and innate hands and
there's no and bang out in the zone
right so what was that one more time on
number three right okay uh was
accountability and consistency okay yeah
let's make sure yeah we got that yes and
then patience being patient with
yourself you're not gonna see results
right away and and the thing is is not
only you're not gonna see results right
away given the fact that you might not
know what you're doing you might not see
results for a long time well I think
you're not able to see results if you're
looking in the wrong places too looking
in the mirror for your result to not
like do I feel a little bit better
mentally as I'm watching another gym
that's a win baby right there yes okay
so so focusing on the results is is is
focusing on the results can or it can be
detrimental or it can make your
motivation that people need the people
that need the motivation focusing on the
results like I said it can tear you down
or it can build you up finding the
correct results and being patient with
them so what are your goals you know I
think laying that out it's important
finding a target is what I call it like
what am I trying to like if you just say
I'm just in 2020 I'm gonna start going
to the gym okay what are you gonna do at
the gym you're gonna go once and you're
gonna make goop yeah did that see yeah I
went to the gym see you're done I went
to the gym I'm done because your goal is
complete if I have a goal and it sounds
crazy but I like to put my stuff out
there I want to be the most athletic
stunt rider
right there's a lot of dudes that are
very very very athletic so if I want to
be the most athletic it's not that I'm
obsessed in chasing this false reality
it's that I better get to work yeah so
that's my goal but if you have a goal
that in 2020 I'm going to the gym like
you said you can go once and your goal
is complete I went to the gym you have
to have something to aim at so what is
your goal is your goal to feel better is
your goal to lose weight is your goal to
to rehab an old injury I know a lot of
people that you know they get an injury
and they oh I can't do that because my
knee and they stop doing and they stop
doing it forever it's never broken right
it's and they stop completely like I
know a lot of dudes are in a lot of
shape or they just like they stopped
working out their legs because their
knees messed up you know they stop and
then and they're just like you're
imbalanced and then you're and then
you're you know your legs are small and
your back and you start having back
problems because you're not working your
core and all you know and all you know
things that I dealt with like I have
torn ligaments in my ankle three times
in my ankle is just absolutely destroyed
but I can't stop working my legs because
that's the bigger part of my body that's
the part that I want to improve but I
have to learn different things I might
have to learn
the muscles around the injury you're
gonna have to really get intricate with
those exact tell them that you need the
strength II yeah so I so having patience
with yourself I think it's a huge like
but you have to in order to do that you
have to set a goal that makes you do
those things and do those steps but you
got to have that patience every day
because you're not even gonna see real
results until you are in it like you see
you take a four-week picture right or or
two month picture a three month picture
like if you get up and and the second
you open your eyes and you're like I
want to see results in the mirror right
now good luck you're gonna get so
frustrated yeah and you're gonna get you
haven't disappointment I think this is
the army people give themselves
disappointment like that sometimes the
same thing I think we talked about last
time about or maybe as with Spencer
about how laying yourself on days you
didn't work out or you know that you ate
where it's like you know that it's like
to fill it's such a silly thing that we
punish ourselves with because even if
you're like like what does it really
mean that today you're this weight
because you ate this thing and then the
next day you didn't it's like do you
know what we do we don't really follow
through with these full thoughts of like
why do I think this means something back
up and be like what does this mean about
my health how do I feel come on you know
how do I feel about the way that I look
yeah I'd never weigh myself
right never yeah never it seems
important that kind of it doesn't thing
we do but it's exactly yeah it's so good
I did have I did at one point had a goal
to like gain size the only time that I
weighed myself is to see okay how do I
feel and again I've been doing this for
a long time so I think when you first
start don't do not ever step on the
scale because how you feel so much more
important than how much you weigh and
how much you and and what you look like
but for me it was like okay if I'm gonna
gain size what's the perfect formula for
what I look like how I feel what am i
way you know I'm saying so if I feel
like okay I look you know I I there was
my goal was to gain a little size but I
feel sluggish what's what's my weight
out right now you know I'm saying right
I find works for you yeah so I don't I
don't ever step on it until I'm like
okay so
right now I like you know how things are
looking I like how I'm feeling I like
the strength that I have but I feel like
I'm a little slow on the cardio I get
I'm getting tired a little fast when I'm
on the bike what do I weigh right and so
I'm like okay I'm one you know 150 okay
maybe I got to dial it back to pounds
you know and then I start tailoring it
my diet and everything towards that
sticking at 148 you know or whatever
whatever that is and so that also comes
to my last point of in yourself and in
your fitness journey and in your
physical and mental health journey you
have to be a scholar like be studying be
studying yourself be studying your body
be studying what works for you and what
doesn't for you and that's what I had to
start doing okay what what was working
for me that's why I changed my workout
program because I couldn't be lifting
like a bodybuilder and wanting to be
agile and be an athlete you know it
doesn't match up I had to study okay
well this is all I know and that's one
of the reasons I was afraid to change it
because I did not know what is a
functional training program look like I
have no idea so forget about it I'm not
changing it right people are gonna you
know okay well this is what I've read
and it's not working so forget it I
tried the Atkins diet
I didn't lose weight I tried keto i
didn't lose weight I don't feel good
forget it try something else and they
say they all try trying everything is
what I've tried I've tried everything
but you tried wanted to make them nail
everything I mean you know I do the same
thing I'm an exaggerator myself and
sometimes all I'll catch myself what am
i doing being dramatic with that [__] a
couple things keep on trying this yeah
life is about
don't you dare just give up no that's
crazy yeah and I had to you know I had
to research like you can't change it
unless you know and I refuse to like no
this is what I know I'm stuck in my ways
this is who this is who I am this is
what I'm doing I couldn't change it the
second I went back and I dialed it back
and I changed what I was doing dude it I
stopped back squatting cuz my back is so
jacked I have four Bulls JISC on my back
I stopped back squatting and I stopped
sprinting so you
just notice it doesn't feel good for me
it doesn't feel good for me and it's
like yeah that's what the ego wants is
the back squat and be heavy and bang
weights around and slam it against the
thing when you put it up but what does
it go against my overall goal is does it
go against my overall goal you know I
want to be athletic I want to be agile I
started doing Sprint's not that long ago
when I haven't ran a long time because
of my back my back started lacking again
my back started hurting I wake up every
day with back pain I did research what
is a good athletic work swimming talked
about this before now I swim I treated
the same ways that sprinting I start
from one side I swim as fast as I can to
and then I go back and forth back and
forth I treat it just like the sprints
but I'm not putting I was aging
literally every step just aging my back
because it's not healed yet
figuring that out is what's important
but to bounce back you need patients do
that you need patients to see that
something doesn't work and to keep going
you have to again bouncing to the next
once you do got to push against some
stuff like okay I'm getting some pain
here like you can't just be like oh
that's not good but exactly
you've been doing this since you were in
sixth grades no okay I've learned about
my body
exactly time and you have the patient
and that's why I think all these things
bounce off each other because it's being
a scholar right then being patient when
something doesn't work and then going
back up to say I'm gonna hold myself
accountable and I have to be consistent
to keep going and to try something else
you know so I think all these things
really really they mesh well together
and they're and they're very important
for the for the fitness goals and I
really think that it's something that
fitness and having a better better your
body's your motor having a better more
improved more healthy better functioning
motor if that's not on your 20 I don't
care if I even to me like people like oh
you know you don't need to workout like
you don't need to workout look at you
could take a day off like so weird a
thing that is still this is that if
bettering my fitness and physical health
is still my one of my top 20 20s and it
will be every single year for the rest
one of the best things you could do it's
a reoccurring cycle it makes everything
in your life better you feel better your
brains better it's
and it will yeah it will be a
reoccurring thing for the rest of my
life it will always be on the top three
for the rest of my life I think it
should be on everybody's lives yeah do
you want people to think like that like
so instead of like I'm gonna go to the
gym once what could they be thinking
instead like let's say they're gonna
start January they're gonna use New
Year's resolutions that January momentum
has everybody else around them it has
that vibe you know let's just grab on to
it it's gonna project these people into
you know hopefully the path of health so
what would you say to them like January
is coming up what's just like some
simple advice you want to give people
outside of expand your goal to just I
would say I want to go back to finding
the benefit like because it's not gonna
be easy especially if you wouldn't
especially if you're it's not a
consistent thing for you starting a new
habit is so hard so finding your goal
that's the first step outside like you
said outside of finding your goal what I
want to say is find that goal set that
goal and then find the benefit because
that's what's gonna keep you motivated
that's what yourself if it ever did
every day so what's the benefit in my
goal here's my goal I have it right but
that goal might not necessarily keep me
going because yeah of course I have a
goal to be skinny but what's the or you
know or more in better shape and feel
better in my everyday but what is the
benefit for it that's what's gonna keep
you motivated like yeah I know my goal
that's great I know my goal there is I
can look at it but what's gonna keep me
eating the same food every day except
for on Sunday when I get myself a break
what's gonna keep me going to the gym
every day I know my goal but what's
gonna keep me going is the benefit I'm
gonna perform better on my bike I'm
gonna I'm gonna the benefit is me
reaching my goal the benefit is of me
eating this kind of bland food every
single day is that I'm going to get
something out of it I get a reward the
reward is being healthy you're gonna get
a reward from staying consistent you're
gonna get a reward from taking your
health more serious you're gonna feel
better you're gonna operate better
you're gonna you're gonna be better in
every aspect of your life because it's
just gonna boost you it's just gonna
boost you right yeah dude in this daily
it's it's a motivational it
it's an intense thing that you got it
you got like alright man come on but
it's but it's also gentle you know what
I mean it's it's this like I'm doing
this because I love you you just a
conversation have it in your head with
yourself like I got to do this like no
don't yourself when those thoughts come
up that are like you know those negative
whiny things and they're like you I want
to go in there and why am I even doing
this and I don't really care about
ihab's and blah blah you got back oh
yeah I'm doing this cuz of this thing oh
yeah I want that oh yeah positivity
gentle on yourself don't get don't get
that cell-fate in there either you know
all right Nate man I notice you cut your
hair it's like a little shorter oh dude
so I have this series that I'm doing on
YouTube right now I just started the
last the first one was a philosophy do I
posted was with my shoes I call it
making room so I got rid of all of my
high-priced Jordans that I collected for
the last 12 years and I'm I realized
that the shoe sitting in the boxes were
not serving me like I had one point been
so into it and so into it but I think
that I connected it with this flesh
thing this outside like sneaker nice
shoe appearance like I enjoyed getting
the shoes I enjoyed what they
represented but I had I think I took 18
pairs to a consignment shop and it I had
to get rid of certain things to make
room for other things in my life and
that was like the metaphor of like
making room and so after I did it I felt
like this relieved like I was like oh
yeah it feels like I'm about to get what
did you anticipate going in like did you
think you were gonna feel relief or you
think you'd be like man this is gonna
suck it and regret this no I knew like I
knew it was gonna feel good because I'm
gonna take the money from it I'm gonna
invest it in something that I really
want to do I'm gonna use it to go to a
seminar or to go to some sort of Eric
Thomas puts on a few different things
with like different kind of schooling
for like speakers or like I'm like it's
funny cuz somebody asked me that I used
to run back and this he's that he's like
he does yeah yeah
and he I told him it's funny because I
told him I go dude I'm just selling he's
because I'm gonna buy him back later
like I like that you know I mean because
because then when I'm in a financial
state where I'm where I can do that I
won't feel like they're the shoes are a
burden you know now I feel like you know
I got a storage unit full of shoes I'm
housing them I'm paying for him it's
like almost a resentment towards them
you know I mean do that with their stuff
yeah so yeah I got rid of him and now
I'm like I get getting the money and I'm
like I can put it somewhere else and so
I look I look back and I was like what
other things that are taking space where
I don't want them to and I cared about
my outside appearance we were so long
and I woke up one day and I was doing my
mirror like I was doing I was like what
what's left and I was like due to my
hair I was so concerned about my hair
for so long and 28 and unfortunately my
hair is starting to thin and so I was
like figuring out different ways to do
it so I was like oh so it looks thick
and it looks how it used to put it but I
but it wasn't laying the same way they
used to because I was so used to doing
it one way for so long like boom like
that it looks good right it wasn't doing
it so I'm like what is it it's thinning
so I would constantly be like going in
the bathroom making sure my hair was
good like because it's like I cared what
people thought like I had this persona
of this physical specimen that I was so
concerned about and I was like so I made
room in my life with getting rid of my
shoes and you know a couple of things
financially a couple ways financially
one I'm getting the money to I can you
know I can shrink the storage unit you
know I mean it's lining up a few ways
I'm gonna get it I'm gonna invest in
myself I mean they're gonna get like I
said seminar new camera one of those
things it's gonna help my content and
help my life and then I think this one
was it was taking up space in my head
like the ego was still there in the in
the way that I
was still concerned about what my hair
was looking like so I was like you know
if I cut it there's no concern there
like it's good it's it's it's gone like
it's just like I get wake up I get out
of shower I still throw some product in
it but I just boom and I don't think
about it or touch it for the rest of the
day there you got more thoughts in here
and now I have more room making room
right now I have more room to worry
about stuff that's important bro it was
so unimportant but it was something that
I is still grasping and it took it takes
a special person to do something like
that like and I and it's it makes me so
happy that I'm in that place in my life
where I can look and go what am I still
holding on to that's not serving me what
am I still holding on to that's still
fleshy or or what am I still holding on
to that's that's an that's part of my
ego and not part of something that I
actually want to do and I recognize that
and I was like dude the hairs gotta go
and it was all it's literally just a
metaphor for me making room for new
things in my life and and what I like
about it is it's not planned like that
series is not planned I woke up one day
my cousin works at the consignment shop
in Portland I woke up one day and I
texted him I said hey I'm about to bring
your 18 pairs of shoes and that was it
and I was like how do I and I texted you
bouncing the idea off of you I said hey
dude you know because we were always
vibing you know I'm like how do I
portray this in like a message and then
I was like I think it's like making room
you know making room for new things and
you were like dude I love it you know
makes it and I was like and so now I'm
like okay now I'm going to do these on a
whim like when I wake up and I feel
something that is blocking me or I
wanted to make room for something else
I'm gonna do it and that's what I did
I woke up and I was like I'm gonna cut
my hair so I no longer am concerned
about checking it making sure it looks
good yeah the the man you've had to
build though in something I noticed that
you're proud of it too which is what I
like to see to it you know it's it's
recognize like the man that you've been
building the last few years is now the
man who is strong enough to just look
himself in the mirror and say what else
needs to go right now
like not dude and I can do it yeah
that's what and like in I've been
building this but it's crazy that you
said proud because I'm proud of myself
that's what I'm saying that I can
literally just look in the mirror and go
dude that thing is taking up space in
your head
that's so much more important things
need to be cut it yeah and and it's a
again it's a metaphor for other things
like what else can I do that with what
else can I get rid of you know I mean
every one of those little hairs as a
metaphor could be man exactly and I hey
you know a lot of the outside I think
the outside appearance is what I had to
tackle first I think it was I changed
the way I dressed too like I have I I
only buy generally black sweatshirts now
and the thing was is like I used to be
like oh I don't want people to see me
wearing the same clothes all the time
but what I do is now as I work a black
sweatshirt every day and I have a white
shirt hanging underneath it and I have
like two or three pairs of pants that
are the same pants but they're just two
or three different ones and and now I'm
over it you know that's what Steve Jobs
did just saying yeah there's a lot of
these these people who they you know
lessen your decisions is obviously that
but it was a lot of our stuff ties us to
our old ways if we're not careful so if
I don't care right if I don't care what
I what I'm dressing if I don't care
about my hair like what other I'm making
so much room my brain for new stuff and
that's what the whole goal was for this
yeah absolutely man I think that we're
always at stages in our life and being
able to be at a mistake if you're able
to recognize that you are at that stage
and so you're like I'm at this stage in
my life whether it's 2 or 3 or whatever
that means but the stage one stuff the
stuff where I had to get these shoes I
had to get these things to make myself
at stage one happy that stage one guy
that Nate he's no longer serving stage 2
stage 4 like so so it just makes sense
you know it's just like what can I take
from stage one that isn't a burden now
and yes recycle it yes into into what
what projects before to my future what
can give me a couple bucks for my future
for money yeah exactly I was listening
in the Eric Thomas podcast and he said
change comes from giving up who you are
now to what you will become
and that's I mean it in every sense of
that that's I had to own that I had to
give up like okay well that's the old
view like you were a sneaker head you're
not a sneaker head anymore like you were
that guy that cared about his appearance
you were that guy that I used to like go
places just to show off my outfits and
my shoes like you know I mean I used to
go places where I would pull up where I
would know girls would be just cuz I got
my hair cut like and just cuz that was
it was so thick it's so fresh so simple
man yeah you're such a more intricate in
in-depth intelligent person than that
and I had to get a and I had to give all
that up and I had to do this so I can
make room for more and and what's coming
to me you know beautiful yeah I like
that man more make room for more yes
start making room in your life for new
stuff oh yeah boom
you